TIMOTHY JORDAN: Hello, I'm Timothy Jordan for "The Developer Show."
This is your update on the coolest developer news
from Google in the last week.
And of course, last week was Google I/O.
"The Developer Show" team was on-site,
broadcasting live from all over Shoreline Amphitheater.
Check out the playlist for keynote recaps, exclusive guest
interviews, and play time in the interactive sandboxes.
If you weren't able to make it to I/O, this is the next best thing.
The link is g.co/io/guide and is in the description below.
Most of the sessions were recorded as well,
and are available at g.co/io/videos.
Now for some of the announcements.
With ML Kit for Firebase, you can
use machine learning to build compelling features on Android
and iOS, regardless of your machine learning expertise.
It's production ready for common use cases
like text recognition and barcode scanning,
allows you to deploy your own custom models,
and it integrates with other Firebase products.
It's now available in beta.
Take a look at the post for screenshots and to get started.
Android Studio 3.2 is available in the Canary channel
and includes features that support the Android P developer
preview, the new Android app bundle, and the Android Jetpack.
Extensive screenshots and details are on the post.
Android Things is Google's managed OS
that enables you to build and maintain Internet
of Things' devices at scale.
Version 1.0 is now available with long-term support
for production devices.
The update also comes with support
for new system on modules, secure software
updates, and a new console interface
to configure hardware peripherals.
Resources are linked from the post.
Developer preview 2 of Wear OS by Google
is now available with support for Actions
on Google and power-related enhancements,
including a new battery saver mode.
The Actions on Google team is making it even easier
for you to get started with the Google Assistant,
drive engagement, and create rich immersive experiences.
Recent updates include the ability to extend your Android
app to the Assistant in more ways, seamless digital content
subscriptions from Google Play, and fully customizable visuals
for display surfaces.
Check out the post for much more detail.
The new Google Photos partner program
gives you the tools and APIs to build photo and video
experiences in your products that are smarter, faster,
and more helpful.
More details and a link to the developer preview are on the post.
Flutter is our mobile app SDK for creating
high-quality native user experiences on iOS and Android.
The third beta release is now available,
with new features that complete core scenarios.
Check out the post for details on customer adoption,
roadmap to release, and links to get started.
As usual, there were a bunch of What's
New sessions and posts from Google I/O.
Here's a quick roundup.
What's new in Android covers all the updates
across development, distribution, and engagement.
What's new in Google Play Console
includes details on Android app bundle, dynamic delivery,
and improvements to help you understand and fix quality
issues in your app or game.
What's new in Android P beta covers adaptive battery,
app actions, slices, and more.
The State of the Web touches on service worker, progressive web
apps, WebAssembly, Lighthouse, and more.
And what's new in Firebase details ML Kit, performance
monitoring, analytics, access management controls, and Test Lab.
Make sure to check out all of the posts
with the links included in the description below.
Please remember to like, subscribe, and share.
I'm Timothy Jordan for "The Developer Show."
Thanks for watching and we'll see you next week.
Hello, I'm Timothy Jordan for the-- yeah,
I'm going to grab some caffeine.
[LAUGHING]
I'll be right back.